[Music]
hello everyone my name is Ricardo and I
am a software engineer in the contol
plane team in business Central and uh we
deal a lot with Administration scenarios
and indeed today I'm here to talk to you
about a new feature that is going to be
introduced with the business Central
2024 Wave 2 and that is the ability to
control the environment access and
administration by partner so without
further Ado let's just jump straight
into the demo so that we can see this
feature live in
action okay so I am logged in into the
usual tenant admin Center as an internal
administrator in this case and I have my
list of environments here on the
environments list page so we can see
that I have two different production
environments for two different
localizations one is for Germany and one
is for us and as a customer I would like
to achieve a setup where I have two
different partners one that could manage
the German environment and one that
could manage the US environment and each
of them should not be able to manage the
other environments so how can I achieve
this now with this new feature so we're
going to have a new setting here
available on the environment Details
page that is called partner access and
right now the value is set to all
Partners this is exactly the default
value that applies and has always
applied until now so let's see how uh
internal admin administrators can change
this in the future so if I click on
modify a new fly out opens and the text
here explains exactly what is the impact
of the toggles that I have ability to
control right now so as I said this is a
default setup but if I want to more
granular control the level of access of
this environment to the different
partners that I have um a relationship
with then I can untoggle this setting
here the second one and that will give
me an additional list uh that shows up
here in the bottom of all the foreign
tenants that have some kind of access to
my customer tenant what does that mean
so um if a tenant has a gdap
relationship with my customer tenant
then it will show as access type gup or
if a tenant has some kind of application
Level access to my customer tenant
meaning that it is home to uh servic to
service application multi-tenant
application that has permissions for
business Central granted in my customer
tenant then it will show as access type
app so in this case I said this is the
German environment and I would only like
the German partner identified by this
tenant ID to have access to control and
administer and view this environment in
the admin Center and also being able to
access the actual environment so log
into that as in this case a service to
service application then I would just
toggle this app this tenant actually and
just press save so when I press save
this setting is applied and now we can
see that the partner access is set to
selected Partners so only the external
tenants that I have explicitly opted in
for this feature will have access to
view and administer this
environment so let's say that I want to
revert this setting back to the default
value that as it used to be then I can
just toggle this again press save this
will access to all the partner tenants
but if I optionally want to instead
disable partner access entirely meaning
that I want this environment only to be
accessible and administered by internal
administrator internal administrators
then I can just un toogle this first
toggle here at the top this will disable
the feature allog together and if I
press
save then the partner access is set to
off so again this will only Grant access
to this environment to internal
administrators so there is a couple of
good to know considerations regarding
this feature first of all that the
partner access settings affect the
authentication of delegated users and
foreign multi-tenant applications so
both of these set of um users or
applications will be affected in terms
of authentication what does it mean so
we said explicitly that both the
environment access in terms of loging to
the environment will be impacted so
these restricted partner tenants will
not be able to log in if they have not
been explicitly allow listed for this
environment and the ability to view and
administer the environment in the tenant
arm Center will also be impacted so the
uh restricted Partners will not be able
to view environments and any related
settings and will not be able to
administer perform any admin
administrative operations on these
environments then again this is a
feature that acts on top of the
requirement of having the tenant level
access consents set up properly so it
does not replace the need for setting up
the gup relationships for external
partner tenants or setting up app
registrations and admin consent for uh
external applications so this is still a
requirement for this feature to work so
on top of having this relationships and
admin consent set up correctly then I
can um react on that and further
restrict the access controls for the
partners that I prefer the other
consideration is that um at the moment
we have a limitation for being able to
restrict the environment access on a
given environment for up to 10 entra
tenants let it be uh tenants uh that
belong to Partners or tenants home to
external foreign multi-tenant
application
so the ability to control the um
environment level access is only
available to internal administrators
then the partner tenants uh will be
affected in terms of
authentication so thank you very much
for listening this was all about this
feature we hope you're going to enjoy
that and have a great rest for the day
thank you